<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Travel on General thoughts on tech and travel.</title>
        <link>https://devfire.io/tags/travel/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Travel on General thoughts on tech and travel.</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 01:32:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devfire.io/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Beyond the Tower or Paris When Nobody&#39;s Looking</title>
        <link>https://devfire.io/p/beyond-the-tower-paris-when-nobodys-looking/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 01:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://devfire.io/p/beyond-the-tower-paris-when-nobodys-looking/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://devfire.io/p/beyond-the-tower-paris-when-nobodys-looking/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Beyond the Tower or Paris When Nobody&#39;s Looking" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was walking past the Eiffel Tower last month and watching all the tourists with their selfie sticks, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but think about the Paris they weren&amp;rsquo;t seeing. You know? The one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t end up on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this garden I stumbled into years ago, tucked behind some apartment buildings in the 11th arrondissement. Jardin Anne Frank, I think it was called. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m remembering wrong. But I remember the way the light filtered through these old chestnut trees and how quiet it was, like the city just stopped breathing for a second. There were maybe three other people there, reading newspapers and feeding pigeons. The benches were those green metal ones that leave marks on your legs, and there was this weird sculpture thing that looked like it was made from old bicycle parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the thing about Paris, though. Everyone&amp;rsquo;s so busy rushing to the Louvre or Notre Dame or whatever that they miss the stuff that actually makes you feel something. Like that bookshop on Rue de Lappe where the owner&amp;rsquo;s cat sits in the window and judges everyone who walks by. The books smell like decades of cigarette smoke and the floorboards creak in this specific way that makes you think about all the people who&amp;rsquo;ve wandered through looking for something they couldn&amp;rsquo;t name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess what gets me is how we&amp;rsquo;ve turned travel into this checklist thing. See the thing, take the photo, move on. But Paris isn&amp;rsquo;t really about the monuments, is it? It&amp;rsquo;s about standing in Place des Vosges at dusk when the light turns everything golden and the kids are playing soccer in the arcade and you can hear someone practicing violin from one of the apartments above. It&amp;rsquo;s messy and imperfect and alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this tiny museum I found once, dedicated to perfume. Musée du Parfum, maybe? The whole place smelled like vanilla and something floral I couldn&amp;rsquo;t identify, and the woman working there told me stories about how they used to make scent from whale vomit. Weird detail to remember, but that&amp;rsquo;s what stuck. That and how her hands moved when she talked, like she was conducting an invisible orchestra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metro tunnels have their own magic too, if you&amp;rsquo;re paying attention. Those long corridors connecting lines, with buskers playing accordion and the sound echoing off the tiles. I saw a guy doing this incredible beatboxing thing once and dropped all my change in his case because it reminded me of being young and thinking the whole world was full of possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I wonder if we&amp;rsquo;re loving these places to death, you know? All of us searching for authenticity while simultaneously destroying it just by being there. But then I think about that garden again, how peaceful it was, how forgotten. Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s hope in the spaces we haven&amp;rsquo;t discovered yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just getting old and nostalgic about things that were never as perfect as I remember them being&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
